Guide to the Edward Bradford Titchener papers,1887-1940.
Titchener, Edward Bradford papers, 1887-1940
- Pamphlets (reprints of E.B.T.'s articles)
  - "The Past Decade in Experimental Psychology," American Journal of Psychology, July 1910 (Box 15)
  - "The Psychology of the New Britannica," American Journal of Psychology, January 1912 (Box 15)
  - "Description vs. Statement of Meaning," American Journal of Psychology, April 1912 (Box 15)
  - "A List of the Writings of James Ward," American Journal of Psychology, July 1912 (Box 15)
  - "Discussion: Professor Martin on the Perlay Experiments," American Journal of Psychology, January 1913 (Box 15)
  - "Discussion: The Method of Examination," American Journal of Psychology, July 1913 (Box 15)
  - "A Note on Sensation and Sentiment," American Journal of Psychology, April 1914 (Box 15)
  - "An Historical Note on the James-Lange Theory of Emotion," American Journal of Psychology, July 1914 (Box 15)
  - "Sensation and System," American Journal of Psychology, April 1915 (Box 15)
  - "Professor Stumpf's Affective Psychology," American Journal of Psychology, April 1917 (Box 15)
  - "Minor Studies from the Psychological Laboratory of Cornell University," American Journal of Psychology, October 1917 (Box 15)
  - "An Anomalous Case of Simple Reaction," American Journal of Psychology, January 1919 (Box 15)
  - "Experimental Psychology: A Retrospect," American Journal of Psychology, July 1925 (Box 15)
  - "Recent Advance in Psychology," The International Monthly, August 1900 (Box 15)
  - "Organic Images," Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods, 21 Jan 1904 (Box 15)
  - "Attention as Sensory Clearness," Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods, 31 March 1910 (Box 15)
  - "A Protest," Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods, 6 July 1911 (Box 15)
  - "A Note on the Sensory Character of Black," Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods, 2 March 1916 (Box 15)
  - "A Further Word on Black," Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods, 23 November 1916 (Box 15)
  - "The Leipsic School of Experimental Psychology," Mind, Vol. I No. 2 (Box 15)
  - "A Psychological Laboratory," Mind, Vol. VII No. 27 (Box 15)
  - "Feeling and Thought: A Reply," Mind, Vol. XX No. 78 (Box 15)
  - "Poetry and Science: The Case of Charles Darwin," Popular Science Monthly, January 1909 (Box 15)
  - "The Effect of Imperceptible Shadows on the Judgement of Distance," Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society, 1907 (Box 15)
  - "On the After-images of Subliminally Colored Stimuli," Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society, 1908 (Box 15)
  - "On Psychology as the Behaviorist Views It," Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society, 31 March 1910 (Box 15)
  - "On the Production of an Artificial Hiss," Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society, 1914 (Box 15)
  - "On Ethnological Tests of Sensation and Perception with Special Reference to Tests of Color Vision and Tactile Discrimination Described in the Reports of the Cambridge Anthropological Expedition to Torres Straits," Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society, 1916 (Box 15)
  - "The Psychological Concept of Clearness," The Psychological Review, January 1917 (Box 15)
  - "President's Address to the Cornell Chapter of the Society of the Sigma Xi", 9 June 1900 (Box 15)
  - "The Psychological Laboratory of Cornell University", 1900 (Box 15)
  - "Ein Versuch die Methode der paarweisen Vergleichung auf die verschiedenen Gefuhlsrichtungen anzuwenden," Leipzig, 1892 (Box 15)
  - "Veber binoculare Wirkengen monocularer Reize," Leipzig, 1892 (Box 15)
  - "The Psychological Laboratory of Cornell University," by Karl M. Dallenbach from American Journal of Psychology, April 1931 (Box 15)
  - "Edward Bradford Titchener," a eulogy by Howard C. Warren from Science, September 2, 1927 (Box 15)
- Autograph collection transferred from library (Box 16)
- Complete photocopy set of J.B. Watson letters (Box 17)
- Photocopy set of William Wundt letters (Box 17)
- Photographs of Titchener's Ithaca residence, ca. 1907 (Box 17)
- Books written by E.B.T. (Box 18)
- Microfilm, mf 26, 27
  Includes E. G. Boring correspondence, 1912, 1914, 1918-1927, and other material.